

SHABARIRAM C P - 10184



ASSISTANT PROFESSOR (SENIOR GRADE) - COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

□ cps@psgitech.ac.in
□ 9597914237
□ Tiruppur

Date Range -

■ 02/May/2017 to 26/Mar/2024

Overview

Very enthusiastic and lively educator. Researcher in the field of Cloud Computing. AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner. Developer -Java/J2EE. I have a great passion towards my teaching profession and molding energetic minds. Published a book entitled "Social Network Analysis". I have published numerous research papers in International journals, International conferences and National conferences. I have to my credit guiding numerous projects at the under graduate and post graduate level in the areas of Cloud Computing (Openstack, AWS, Windows Azure), Big Data Analytics (Apache Hadoop and Apache Spark) and Machine Learning. My expertise lies in teaching Programming - C /C++/ Java, Operating Systems, Data Structures, Computer Architecture, Compiler Design, Cloud Computing and Data Analytics.

Work Experience

Total Exp: 0.0 year(s) / Current Exp: year(s)

02-05-2017 - Present Assistant Professor (Sr. Gr.)

PSG Institute of Technology and Applied Research

05-06-2014 - 30-04-2017 Assistant Professor

Sri Shakthi Institute of Technology and Applied Research

Education

2014 PG

ANNA UNIVERSITY
ANNA UNIVERSITY

CHENNAI

2012 UG

ANNA UNIVERSITY ANNA UNIVERSITY TRICHIRAPPALLI

PHD

ANNA UNIVERSITY
Kongu Engineering College
Erode

Computer/IT Skills C++ Java Python (R)Scala Ubuntu ` Cent-OS Linux-mint Windows EdgeCloudSim **Cloud-Computing Edge-Computing Big-Data-Analytics** Openstack AWS Hadoop Google-APP-Engine R-Studio Languages Known ENGLISH TAMIL **Subjects Handled Cloud-Computing Data-Structures Algorithms** Theory-of-Computation Compiler-Design **Object-Oriented-Programming Competitions** Total : (1 Solve-a-thon , 🖟 CII, 🊳 II PRIZE **Competitive Exam Scores Total** : (1 **NET** ⊗ UGC NET, ■ 96 Percentile, ■ 2019

Total : (1

IEI India

Membership in Professional Bodies

Total: (7) Citation: (

JOURNAL Total: (3) Citation: (2) PRIYA PONNUSAMY P VIDHYA PRIYA R SHABARIRAM C P FILE RETRIEVAL AND STORAGE IN THE OPEN SOURCE CLOUD TOOL USING DIGITAL BIPARTITE AND DIGIT COMPACT PREFIX INDEXING METHOD **® WILEY** PRIYA PONNUSAMY P SHABARIRAM C P CLIENT CLASSIFICATION AND DYNAMIC PRICING OF RESOURCES IN CLOUD USING CLOUD SIMULATOR **® AURICLE GLOBAL SOCIETY OF EDUCATION AND RESEARCH** ■ Volume No: 11,
■ ISBN/ISSN No: 23218169,
■ Issue No: 7 S,
■ 2023 SHABARIRAM C P SHANTHI N PRIYA PONNUSAMY P COMPUTATIONAL OFFLOADING IN VEHICULAR EDGE COMPUTING USING MULTIPLE AGENT-BASED DETERMINISTIC POLICY GRADIENT ALGORITHM AND GENERATIVE ADVERSARIAL NETWORKS **® INDERSCIENCE** 🖺 Volume No: 44, 🖹 ISBN/ISSN No: 17438225, 🖹 Issue No: 4, 🛗 2023 **CONFERENCE-PAPER** Total: (4) Citation: (0) PRIYA PONNUSAMY P SHABARIRAM C P LOAD BALANCING WITH HASHMAP IN CLOUD COMPUTING USING CLOUD SIMULATOR **® SPRINGER, SINGAPORE** SHANTHI N PRIYA PONNUSAMY P PREMA R SOWMIYA PRIYA R S

OPTIMIZING VIRTUAL MACHINE DOWNTIME IN LIVE MIGRATION USING THE LEAST FREQUENTLY USED SERVICE-**BASED PRE-COPY ALGORITHM**

® IEEE XPLORE

2023

PRIYA PONNUSAMY P SHABARIRAM C P UMAYAL V R SUSMETA A

CLOSEST CELESTIAL BODY SEARCH USING KD TREES

® IEEE XPLORE

■ 2023

CHARADIDAM CD	PRIYA PONNUSAMY F

SEMANTIC SIMILARITY BASED AUTOMATED ANSWER SCRIPT EVALUATION SYSTEM USING MACHINE LEARNING PIPELINE AND NATURAL LANGUAGE

® SPRINGER, SINGAPORE

■ Volume No: 1439,
■ ISBN/ISSN No: 978-981-19-9818-8,
■ 2023

PUBLISHED

Total: 2

SIVAGANESAN D KALA I PRIYA PONNUSAMY P SHABARIRAM C P

Secure the communication between IOT devices in Vehicular Network using authenticated encryption with associated data

Publication No:42/2022

Indian Patent, 2022

SHABARIRAM C P PRIYA PONNUSAMY P KALA I SIVAGANESAN D

Secure and Efficient Key Management Protocol for Wireless Communication

Indian Patent,
 2023

Publication No:02/2024

⊗ Springer, Singapore, 🗎 2023

SMART DATA INTELLIGENCE

Springer, Singapore,
2022

PRIYA PONNUSAMY P SHABARIRAM C P

GUEST LECTURE Total: (3)

TECHNICAL TALK ON "CRACKING GATE EXAM - ALGORITHMS AND DATA STRUCTURES" IS CONDUCTED IN ASSOCIATION WITH PSGI STUDENTS' CHAPTER, THE INSTITUTION OF ENGINEERS (INDIA).

⊗ COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2020-08-01 to 2020-08-01

TALK ON CRACKING GATE EXAM - DATA STRUCTURES

⊗ COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2021-05-06 to 2021-05-06

TALK ON CRACKING GATE EXAM - DESIGN AND ANALYSIS OF ALGORITHMS

⊗ COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2021-05-13 to 2021-05-13

OTHERS Total: 14

VALUE ADDED COURSE ON 17CS03 IOT IN INDUSTRY 4.0 ⊗ COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2017-06-28 to 2017-07-03 VALUE ADDED COURSE ON 17CS01 CODING GUIDELINES FOR C PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES **⊗** COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2018-01-22 to 2018-01-25 24 HOURS NON-STOP TRAILHEAD STUDENT CHAMPIONSHIP 2018 (LEARNATHON) **⊗** COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2018-02-02 to 2018-02-03 VALUE ADDED COURSE ON 18CS01 AWS AND AZURE CLOUD MANAGEMENT **⊗** COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2018-06-11 to 2018-06-14 VALUE ADDED COURSE ON 17CS01 CODING GUIDELINES FOR C PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES **⊗** COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2019-01-28 to 2019-01-31 SHORT TERM COURSE ON AWS ACADEMY CLOUD FOUNDATIONS **⊗** COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2019-08-28 to 2019-10-30 **VALUE ADDED COURSE ON 19CS02 CAD FOR VLSI ⊗** COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2019-12-11 to 2019-12-14 VALUE ADDED COURSE ON 19CS01 CODING GUIDELINES FOR OBJECT ORIENTED PROGRAMMING **⊗** COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2020-02-11 to 2020-02-14 VALUE ADDED COURSE ON 18CS01 AWS AND AZURE CLOUD MANAGEMENT **⊗** COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2020-11-10 to 2020-11-13 VALUE ADDED COURSE ON 19CS01 CODING GUIDELINES FOR OBJECT ORIENTED PROGRAMMING **⊗** COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2021-02-02 to 2021-02-05

TOP FOOLS 2022

PROJECT EXHIBITION IN ITECH EXPO 2022

⊗ COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2022-04-01 to 2022-04-01

VAC ON 23CS04 CLOUD COMPUTING EXPERIENCE WITH BUSINESS USE CASES

INDUSTRY ACADEMIA CONCLAVE 2023 - CSE

CONFERENCE Total: 1

NATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMMUNICATION, COMPUTING AND SYSTEM DESIGN (NC3SD'19)

⊗ COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2019-03-19 to 2019-03-19

SEMINAR Total: 3

RESEARCH TALK ON DATA SCIENCE AND DEEP LEARNING MODELS

② COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **❷** 3600, **■ 2020-01-29 to 2020-01-29**

ARCESIUM INTERVIEW - THE IN AND OUT

⊗ COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, **■** 2021-06-17 to 2021-06-17

HOW TO SET OFF FOR PLACEMENT AND HIGHER STUDIES

Total: 41

TECHNICAL FEST	Total: 1
Solve-a-thon: Youth, Skills and the Workforce of the future contest © CII Coimbatore, © 2018-09-30 to 2018-09-30	
FDP	Total : 22
Faculty Development Program on Hadoop Technology © CTS Coimbatore, © 2017-09-23 to 2017-09-23	
4 day Faculty Development Program on Cloud Computing Architecture (AWS) ® ICT Academy, © 2018-01-22 to 2018-01-25	
one week Faculty Development Program on Oracle Database Foundations ® ICT Academy, © 2019-08-19 to 2019-08-23	
Professional Ethics & Sustainability ® AICTE, © 2020-02-01 to 2020-03-31	
Communication Skills, Modes and Knowledge Dissemination	
online Faculty Development Program on Emerging trends in Ethical hacking and cyber security	
virtual Faculty Development Program on Agile methodology ® REVA University, 2020-07-14 to 2020-07-18	
Artificial Intelligence and Data Analytics for Automation ® Karunya Institute of Technology and Sciences, Coimbatore., © 2020-07-27 to 2020-07-31	
5-day online FDP on the theme Inculcating Universal Human Values in Technical Education	

12 Hours Faculty Development Program on Android Development with Kotlin		
⊗ ICT Academy , iii 2021-07-26 to 2021-07-30		
online Faculty Development Program on Computer Architecture		
® PSG CARE, 📾 2021-09-06 to 2021-09-10		
Introduction to Industry 4.0 and Industrial Internet of Things		
⊗ NPTEL, ■ INTERNAL, □ 2022-06-01 to 2022-10-31		
Applied Accelerated Artificial Intelligence		
⊗ NPTEL,		
Instructional Planning and Delivery		
⊗ AICTE,		
Technology Enabled Learning and Life-long Self-learning		
⊗ AICTE,		
Student Assessment and Evaluation		
® AICTE,		
Creative Problem Solving, Innovation and Meaningful R&D		
® AICTE,		
Institutional Management & Administrative Procedures		
Two day Faculty Development Program on Cyber security and Digital Forensics		
Faculty Development Program on Data Analytics using KNIME		
Big Data Computing		
big bata compating		

⊗ ICT Academy, ■ 2023-09-25 to 2023-09-29	
WORKSHOP	Total : 6
one day workshop on Technical textiles and capabilities of PSGITECH COE INDUTECH	
⊗ PSGITECHS COE INDUTECH, Neelambur., 🗎 2017-10-16 to 2017-10-16	
workshop on Activity based learning	
⊗ PSG CARE,	
faculty workshop using Salesforce Trailhead	
® ICT Academy, 🗎 2018-06-15 to 2018-06-15	
one day workshop on Effective use of Moodle 3.5	
⊗ PSG iTech,	
online session on conduct of online laboratory classes - a demo	
⊗ PSG CARE,	
online session on Effective method of handling online classes	
⊗ PSG CARE,	
OTHERS	Total : 10
37th Edition of BRIDGE 2019 - CHENNAI	
⊗ ICT Academy,	
six week intensive training program on educational technology (PET 2019)	
⊗ PSG CARE,	
Orientation towards Technical Education & Curriculum Aspects	
⊗ AICTE, 🗎 2020-02-01 to 2020-03-31	
Session 2 of Sky Campus - Webinar on the theme leading in VCUDA World	
⊗ ICT Academy,	

one week Faculty Development Program on Data Analytics using Python

⊗ ICT Academy,	
webinar on AWS cloud practitioner essentials ® East Point College of Engineering and Technology, Bangalore., © 2020-07-15 to 2020-07-15	
one week STTP on Artificial Intelligence in Health Care	
webinar on Value of IEEE Publications in Research and Career Development ® EBSCO, 2020-07-20 to 2020-07-20	
webinar on Functional Verification of complex SoC designs using UVM	
One year certificate course on Cyber Security and Data Science ® PSG CARE, © 2021-01-01 to 2021-12-31	
SEMINAR	Total : 1
webinar on Machine Learning using R	
ORIENTATION PROGRAMME	Total : 1
Orientation program ® PSG CARE, © 2017-06-21 to 2017-06-23	

ICT Academy Convergence 2020

APPRECIATION FOR COORDINATING DIAGNOSTIC TEST 2023

🖹 STUDENT INDUCTION PROGRAMME 2023, 📠 INTRA-COLLEGE, 📠 PSG ITECH, 🥮 PSG iTech, 📾 2023-09-01

APPRECIATION FOR MENTORING PROFESSIONAL READINESS

🖹 NAAN MUDHALVAN, 📠 STATE, 📠 PSG ITECH, 🛭 IBM, 🛗 2023-06-28

APPRECIATION FOR COORDINATING DIAGNOSTIC TEST 2022

🖹 STUDENT INDUCTION PROGRAMME 2022 -23, 📠 INTRA-COLLEGE, 📠 PSG ITECH, 🧭 PSGi Tech, 📾 2022-08-31

APPRECIATION FOR COORDINATING PROFICIENCY MODULE TEST 2021

🖹 STUDENT INDUCTION PROGRAMME 2021, 📠 INTER-COLLEGE, 📠 PSG ITECH, 🕮 PSG iTech, 📾 2021-10-27

APPRECIATION FOR COORDINATING PROFICIENCY MODULE TEST AND FEEDBACK SESSION 2021

PSG ITECH, Inter-college, PSG ITECH, PSG ITECH, PSG ITECH, 2020-11-24

APPRECIATION FOR BOOK PUBLICATION

🖹 PASCO LAB INAGURATION, 📠 INTRA-COLLEGE, 📠 PSG ITECH, 🚳 PSG iTech, 📾 2020-01-14

BEST TUTOR

FACULTY AWARD - 2019, LEDEPARTMENT, PSG ITECH, PSG ITECH, 2019-08-14

BEST FINAL YEAR PROJECT AWARD 2018-19

🖹 ALUMNI INDUCTION PROGRAMME 2015-19, 📠 INTRA-COLLEGE, 📠 PSG ITECH, 🕮 PSG iTech Alumni Association, 📾 2019-04-04

AWS CERTIFIED CLOUD PRACTITIONER

APPRECIATION FOR SETTING UP PRIVATE CLOUD

🖹 DAKSHA 2018, 💄 INTRA-COLLEGE, 💄 PSG ITECH, 🥒 PSG iTech, 🗐 2018-03-28

APPRECIATION FOR NEW INDIA STUDENT CHAMPIONSHIP 2018

🖹 NEW INDIA STUDENT CHAMPIONSHIP 2018, 📠 STATE, 📠 PSG ITECH, 🕮 ICT Academy Salesforce, 📾 2018-02-03

This is system generated profile on 26-03-2024

Laudea[®] - Copyright © 2024 <u>PSG Software Technologies</u>